Benny H, Full Stack Developer

Bennyh960@gmail.com, 052-4874600, LinkedIn, GitHub

For the past six years, I have worked as a **Process Engineer** with experience in process design, development, and project management. With curiosity and passion for learning, I am now looking for my next challenge as a **Full Stack Developer**. I am skilled in Front-End and Back-End technologies and have plenty of motivation to learn and succeed.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full Stack Developer, Dealigence (Internship) (2022-)

- Developing "Connection Assessment" API, a product that aims to evaluate connections strength between entities stored in DB using **Postgres(SQL)**.
- Design of the required tables and their relationships (one-to-many, many-to-many, polymorphic association).
- Retrieve data using scrapers, Parse it and load into the database (NodeJS, Puppeteer, Scrape-it, Sequelize ORM).
- Building complex queries focusing on efficiency (indexing, window function).

Process Engineer, Intel (2018-2021)

- Tool owner of production machines, responsible for tool performance, data, writing work plans, troubleshooting and Validation.
- Project management to improve Tool availability and quality performance.

Process Engineer, Merck (2015-2018)

- Design and develop technological production processes, problem-solving and improving product quality.
- Pilots operation, process improvement, and writing work plans.

EDUCATION

2022- 2022 Full Stack Developer Bootcamp - AppelSeeds.

- Intensive 6-months, 720 hours training program that encourages self-led.
- learning and group projects that simulate real-world development teams including Git workflow.
- Learning and applying front-end skills such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- React and back-end skills such as Node.js and MongoDB database.
- Social media mid-project in FE only, including CRUD and Chat. (Git, Demo).
- Social media Final-project (MERN), including JWT authenticate, Websocket Chat, full CRUD including.
 (Git, Demo)
- Python self-learn with a 2D game project from the Pygame library.

2011- 2015 B.Sc in Chemical Engineering, SCE (Ashdod)

- Graduated with excellence.
- Average 93 and receipt of departmental certificates of excellence, excellence in scientific tutoring, and receipt of a scholarship of excellence.

Languages Hebrew native speaker English Highly proficient